They will get their execution... I will get my freedom.
Iron Lung is a horror, science fiction film directed by Markiplier.
An ocean of blood.
The only hope left after The Quiet Rapture.
In the rusting halls of crumbling space stations, the last remnants of
humanity craft a submarine to explore the bleeding depths...
and weld one soul inside to pilot it.
But hope in this void is as illusionary as the starlight.
This is not an expedition.
It's an execution.
The Convict, played by Markiplier.
Iron Lung is an upcoming American science fiction horror film written, directed, executive
produced, edited by, and starring Mark Fischbach in his feature directorial debut.
Produced and distributed by Markiplier Studios, it is an adaptation of the 2022 video game of the same name by David Szymanski, and also
stars Caroline Rose Kaplan, Seán McLoughlin, Szymanski, Troy Baker, Elsie Lovelock, and Isaac McKee in supporting roles.
Development on a Iron Lung film adaptation began in April 2023, when Fischbach, better known
as Markiplier on YouTube, announced he would be adapting the game into film.
Fischbach, who had previously played Iron Lung on his channel, stated the film would
be self-written, self-financed, and star himself alongside Kaplan.
Szymanski also confirmed that he had been involved with the film since pre-production, assisting with its
screenplay and being on set during filming, and that he would have a small cameo in the film.
Fischbach also co-produced alongside Will Hyde and Jeff Guerrero.
Iron Lung is scheduled to be released on January 30, 2026 in the United States,
Canada, United Kingdom, Ireland, Australia, New Zealand, and elsewhere.
The film explores themes of future, moon, submarine, boat, expedition.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and thought_provoking.